A Guide to the Virginius Dabney Papers 1941-1971
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Virginius Dabney Papers 1941-1971
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7690-n
This holding consists of 28 boxes of material.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This holding was acquired as a gift.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of Virginius Dabney contain extensive correspondence carried on by Dabney as editor of the Richmond Times-Dispatch, in his personal life, and as a Pulitzer Prize- winning author. Other materials deal with his books such as Below the Potomac, The Dry Messiah, and Liberalism in the South, and much useful material collected as research material for these books is present. There is extensive material on the American Society of Newspaper Editors which Dabney served in various capacities including president. A great deal of useful material on race relations, African Americans, the N.A.A.C.P., etc., is present. Recent political history of Virginia is strongly represented in Dabney's correspondence as editor of Virginia's leading newspaper, and in his personal correspondence with figures such as Senator A. Willis Robinson, Francis Pickens Miller, and Senator Carter Glass.
Contents List
- A 1962-1965 (Box 1)
- A 1962-1965 (Box 1)
- A 1965-1970 (Box 1)
- Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relation, Frank Bane 1966 (Box 1)
- American Council on Education 1966 (Box 1)
- American Heritage 1962-1965 (Box 1)
- American Legion 1966 (Box 1)
- American Society of Newspaper Editors 1966-1969 (Box 1)
- Andress, T. Coleman, 1899- 1947-1968 (Box 1)
- Arnold, Remmie Le Roy, 1894- 1943-1965 (Box 1)
- Articles submitted for publication 1965-1967 (Box 2)
- Awards 1966 (Box 2)
- Ayers, Col. H.M. 1942-1948 (Box 2)
- Ba-Bh 1950-1965 (Box 2)
- Ba-Bh 1950-1965 (Box 2)
- Ba-Bh 1950-1965 (Box 2)
- Baldwin, Hanson Weightman, 1903- 1942-1968 (Box 2)
- Barrett, Clifton Waller, 1901- 1960-1968 (Box 2)
- Barrow, W.J. 1960-1968 (Box 2)
- Barrow, W. J. 1963-1964 (Box 3)
- Barter Theater 1948-1964 (Box 3)
- Bemiss, Fitzgerald 1963-1967 (Box 3)
- Bemiss, Samuel M. 1954-1967 (Box 3)
- Benedict, Bertram 1961-1963 (Box 3)
- Berkeley, Francis 1947-1968 (Box 3)
- Berkness, I. Russell 1951-1968 (Box 3)
- Bi-Bq 1962-1965 (Box 3)
- Bird, Lloyd C. 1944-1966 (Box 3)
- Blanton, Mrs. Wynham B. 1946-1947 (Box 3)
- Bocock, Mrs. John H. 1951-1978 (Box 4)
- Bodine & Associates, Inc.; Stanley L. Cahn-Aubrey Bodine 1962-1967 (Box 4)
- Book Reviews by Virginius Dabney 1967 (Box 4)
- Booth, Lea--Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges 1956-1966 (Box 4)
- Bosher, Mrs. Lewis, Jr.; The Latrobe Theater 1964-1968 (Box 4)
- Boushall, Thomas C. 1943-1968 (Box 4)
- Bowie, Dr. W. Russell 1942-1964 (Box 4)
- Br-Bt 1962-1965 (Box 4)
- Br-Bt 1966-1968 (Box 4)
- Braxton, H. Galt 1947 (Box 5)
- Brown, Mrs. D. Tucker 1941-1968 (Box 5)
- Brownfield, Allan C. 1963-1967 (Box 5)
- Bryan, The Hon. Albert Vickers, 1899- 1962-1967 (Box 5)
- Bryan, Joseph, III, 1904- 1958-1968 (Box 5)
- Bryan, Wright, 1906-- 1942-1961 (Box 5)
- Bu-Bz 1962-1965 (Box 5)
- Bu-Bz 1964-1968 (Box 5)
- Buck, J.L. Blair 1943-1945 (Box 5)
- Bulletin, Miles Wolff, Frederic G. Pitts 1956-1961 (Box 5)
- The Bulletin 1971, 5 issues (Box 5)
- Bush, Monroe 1960-1967 (Box 5)
- Byrd, Harry Flood, Jr., 1917- 1943-1968 (Box 5)
- Ca-Cg 1962-1965 (Box 6)
- Ca-Cg 1966-1968 (Box 6)
- Cannon, Edmund W. 1964-1968 (Box 6)
- Carter, Hodding, 1907-- 1946-1966 (Box 6)
- Catterrall, Ralph T. 1955-1968 (Box 6)
- Ch-Cn 1962-1965 (Box 6)
- Chambers, Lenoir 1949-1968 (Box 6)
- Cheek, Leslie, Jr., 1908--; Director, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts 1952-1968 (Box 6)
- Citizens' Advisory Committee on Economic Education 1965 (Box 6)
- Clark, Gaylord Lee 1951-1967 (Box 6)
- Co-Cq 1962-1965 (Box 6)
- Co-Cq 1965-1968 (Box 7)
- Community College 1966 (Box 7)
- Cosby, Joseph Hathaway, 1902--; President, Hargrave Military Academy 1965 (Box 7)
- Couch, W.T. 1963-1966 (Box 7)
- Country Club of Virginia 1965-1968 (Box 7)
- Country Club of Virginia 1965-1968 (Box 7)
- Cox, General Edwin, 1902-- 1956-1968 (Box 7)
- Cr-Cz 1962-1965 (Box 7)
- Cr-Cz 1965-1968 (Box 7)
- Crinkley, Richmond 1966-1969 (Box 7)
- Da-Dn 1950-1969 (Box 7)
- Da-Dn 1957-1965 (Box 8)
- Da-Dn 1957-1965 (Box 8)
- Daniels, Jonathan Worth, 1902-- 1941-1966 (Box 8)
- Daniels, Jonathan 1941-1966 (Box 8)
- Darden, Colgate Whitehead, 1897-- 1947-1969 (Box 8)
- Davis, Curtis Carroll 1964-1968 (Box 9)
- Davis, Dr. John Staige, 1900-- 1956-1968 (Box 9)
- de Boinville, David 1961-1968 (Box 9)
- Department of Community Colleges 1966 (Box 9)
- Dillard, Hardy Cross, 1902-- 1965-1968 (Box 9)
- Do-Dz 1962-1965 (Box 9)
- Do-Dz 1966-1971 (Box 9)
- Dowdey, Clifford, 1904-- 1955-1967 (Box 9)
- Duke University Board of Advisors for Southern Studies 1966-1967 (Box 9)
- E 1962-1965 (Box 9)
- E 1966-1968 (Box 9)
- Edmunds, Murrell, 1898-- (Box 9)
- Educational Television Corp. 1965-1966 (Box 10)
- Episcopal High School 1953-1961 (Box 10)
- Fa-Fn 1962-1965 (Box 10)
- Fa-Fn 1965-1968 (Box 10)
- Fernsworth, Lawrence 1941-1963 (Box 10)
- Fitzroy, Col. Herbert W.K.; Pres., University Center in Virginia, Inc. 1966 (Box 10)
- Fo-Fz 1962-1965 (Box 10)
- Fo-Fz 1965-1968 (Box 10)
- Foundation for Independent Junior Colleges in Virginia; Jesse R. Barnet 1966-1968 (Box 10)
- Founder's Day Address, University of Virginia April 13, 1966 (Box 10)
- Fulbright Award, Cambridge University England Lectures 1954-1964 (Box 10)
- Ga-Gk 1962-1965 (Box 11)
- Ga-Gk 1966-1969 (Box 11)
- Gl-Gz 1962-1965 (Box 11)
- Gl-Gz 1965-1968 (Box 11)
- Governor's Conference on Education Correspondence 1966-1967 (Box 11)
- Haa-Hal 1962-1965 (Box 11)
- Haa-Hal 1966-1968 (Box 11)
- Hahn, Thomas Marshall, Jr., 1926- 1964-1965 (Box 11)
- Hall, Grover C., Jr. 1948-1966 (Box 11)
- Hamilton, John Andrew, 1907-- 1960-1967 (Box 11)
- Ham-Hd 1962-1965 (Box 12)
- Ham-Hd 1966-1968 (Box 12)
- Harbison, Clinton M. 1952-1968 (Box 12)
- Harper's Magazine: The Good Southern Universities 1964-1966 (Box 12)
- Harrison, Albertis Sydney, 1907--; Former Governor of Virginia 1961-1965 (Box 12)
- Haynie, Hugh, 1927-- 1956-1964 (Box 12)
- He-Hn 1962-1965 (Box 12)
- He-Hn 1965-1968 (Box 12)
- Ho-Ht 1962-1965 (Box 12)
- Ho-Ht 1965-1968 (Box 13)
- Howland, William S. 1944-1968 (Box 13)
- Hu-Hz 1962-1965 (Box 13)
- Hu-Hz 1966-1968 (Box 13)
- Humelsine, Carlisle Hubbard, 1925- 1956-1968 (Box 13)
- I 1962-1965 (Box 13)
- I 1966-1968 (Box 13)
- J 1962-1965 (Box 13)
- J 1966-1968 (Box 13)
- Jack Jouett published The Iron Worker and Correspondence 1962-1968 (Box 13)
- James, Arthur W. 1951-1967 (Box 14)
- Jamestowne Society, The 1966-1968 (Box 14)
- John, Jay W. 1965-1966 (Box 14)
- Johston, J. Ambler 1959-1968 (Box 14)
- Jones, Jenkin Lloyd, 1911- 1960-1965 (Box 14)
- Ka-Kk 1962-1965 (Box 14)
- Ka-Kk 1966-1968 (Box 14)
- Kl-Kz 1962-1965 (Box 14)
- Kl-Kz 1966-1968 (Box 14)
- Klu Klux Klan 1965 (Box 14)
- Krock, Arthur, 1886-- 1949-1969 (Box 14)
- La-Ld 1962-1965 (Box 14)
- Lawton, Edward P. 1961-1966 (Box 14)
- Le-Ln 1962-1965 (Box 14)
- Le-Ln 1965-1968 (Box 14)
- Lo-Lz 1962-1965 (Box 15)
- Lo-Lz 1967-1968 (Box 15)
- London, Roger; Consul of the Republic of France 1966-1969 (Box 15)
- Ma-Mb 1962-1965 (Box 15)
- Ma-Mb 1966-1968 (Box 15)
- Malone, Dr. Dumas, 1892- 1941-1967 (Box 15)
- Mapp, Alf J., Jr. 1948-1968 (Box 15)
- Markle Foundation, John M. Russell 1949-1968 (Box 15)
- Marsh, John O., Jr. 1958-1968 (Box 16)
- Correspondence with John Masefield 1957-1958 (Box 16)
- Mc-Md 1962-1965 (Box 16)
- Mc-Md 1965-1969 (Box 16)
- McDowell, Charles R. J. 1966-1968 (Box 16)
- McFarlane, William H. 1966-1968 (Box 16)
- Me-Mn 1962-1965 (Box 16)
- Me-Mn 1966-1968 (Box 16)
- Meacham, William Shands, 1900-- 1966-1968 (Box 16)
- Meade, Prof. Robert Douthat, 1903-- 1947-1967 (Box 16)
- Mo-Mz 1962-1965 (Box 17)
- Mo-Mz 1965-1970 (Box 17)
- N 1962-1965 (Box 17)
- N 1966-1969 (Box 17)
- Newton, Karl 1955-1968 (Box 17)
- Newton, Michael 1955-1965 (Box 17)
- O 1962-1965 (Box 17)
- O 1948-1968 (Box 18)
- Old Dominion Foundation Fellowship Program Advisory Committee 1966-1968 (Box 18)
- Pa-Ph 1962-1965 (Box 18)
- Pa-Ph 1965-1968 (Box 18)
- Parker, Alex Wilson, 1898-- 1966-1968 (Box 18)
- Paschall, Dr. Davis Young, 1911-- 1966-1968 (Box 18)
- Perts, John C. 1966-1968 (Box 18)
- Pi-Pz 1961-1965 (Box 19)
- Pi-Pz 1966-1968 (Box 19)
- Pomfret, John Edwin, 1898-- 1966-1968 (Box 19)
- Powell, Lewis Franklin, Jr., 1907-- 1951-1968 (Box 19)
- Powell, Lewis Franklin, Jr. 1951-1968 (Box 19)
- Powell, Lewis Franklin, Jr. 1951-1968 (Box 19)
- Pulitzer Prize 1948 (Box 20)
- Pulitzer Prize--Congratulations 1948 (Box 20)
- Pulitzer Prize--Congratulations (Box 20)
- Pulitzer Prize--Congratulations 1948 (Box 20)
- Pulitzer Prize--Congratulations 1948 (Box 20)
- Putnam, Carleton, 1901-- 1966-1968 (Box 21)
- Q 1962-1964 (Box 21)
- Q 1968 (Box 21)
- Ra-Rn 1962-1965 (Box 21)
- Ra-Rn 1966-1968 (Box 21)
- Requests for copies of editorials 1967-1968 (Box 21)
- Requests for Permission to Reprint 1967-1968 (Box 21)
- Richmond International Council 1964-1968 (Box 21)
- Richmond Professional Institute 1967 (Box 21)
- "Richmond's Quiet Revolution" Saturday Review, February 20, 1964 1963-1964 (Box 21)
- Ro-Rz 1962-1965 (Box 22)
- Ro-Rz 1966-1968 (Box 22)
- The Rotunda, University of Virginia: Article and Correspondence 1965-1966 (Box 22)
- Sa-Sb 1962-1965 (Box 22)
- Sa-Sb 1966-1968 (Box 22)
- Sales Tax Program, Times Dispatch 1965 (Box 22)
- Saturday Review: Cheating Article 1965-1968 (Box 22)
- Saturday Review: Portugese Bullfight Article 1966 (Box 22)
- Sc-Sd 1962-1965 (Box 22)
- Sc-Sd 1965-1968 (Box 22)
- Se-Sj 1962-1965 (Box 23)
- Se-Sj 1965-1968 (Box 23)
- Sigma Delta Chi, National 1963-1967 (Box 23)
- Sigma Delta Chi, Richmond Chapter 1967 (Box 23)
- Sk-Ss 1962-1965 (Box 23)
- Sk-Ss 1966-1968 (Box 23)
- Southern Newspaper Publishers Association 1941-1960 (Box 23)
- Southern Regional Education Board Program Committee 1966-1968 (Box 24)
- Speaking Engagements 1962-1964 (Box 24)
- St-Sz 1962-1965 (Box 24)
- St-Sz 1965-1968 (Box 24)
- Stonewall Jackson Memorial, Inc. 1954-1962 (Box 24)
- T 1962-1965 (Box 25)
- T 1962-1965 (Box 25)
- T 1962-1965 (Box 25)
- T 1966-1968 (Box 25)
- Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation, Inc. 1967 (Box 25)
- Tucker, Henry St. George, 1853-1932 1951-1955 (Box 25)
- U-V 1962-1965 (Box 25)
- U-V 1962-1965 (Box 25)
- University of Virginia Chair--Sir Winston Churchill 1965 (Box 26)
- Valentine Museum 1959-1967 (Box 26)
- Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges 1966 (Box 26)
- Virginia Museum of Fine Arts; Fred Haseltine 1965-1966 (Box 26)
- Virginia Quarterly Review: "The Pace is Important" 1965 (Box 26)
- Virginia Record; Blog. Bishop John J. Russell 1967 (Box 26)
- Wa-Wd 1962-1965 (Box 26)
- Wa-Wd 1965-1970 (Box 26)
- We-Wh 1962-1965 (Box 26)
- We-Wh 1966-1968 (Box 26)
- Wi-Wz 1961-1965 (Box 26)
- Wi-Wz 1964-1969 (Box 26)
- Wi-Wz 1964-1969 (Box 26)
- X-Y-Z 1962-1965 (Box 26)
- X-Y-Z 1965-1968 (Box 26)
- Letters from Prominent People
  - Ackerman, C.W. 1933 (Box 27)
  - Ackerman, C.W. 1933 (Box 27)
  - Acheson, Dean Gooderham, 1893- 1949 (Box 27)
  - Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951 1935 (Box 27)
  - Agar, Herbert Sebastian, 1897-- 1939 (Box 27)
  - Allen, Robert Sharon, 1923-- (Box 27)
  - Alsop, Stewart Johonnot Oliver, 1914-- 1971 (Box 27)
  - Anderson, Paul Y. (Box 27)
  - Angoff, Charles, 1902-- 1926 (Box 27)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1893-- 1957 (Box 27)
  - Astor, Nancy Witcher (Langhorne) viscountess, 1879-1964 1938 (Box 27)
  - Bakeless, John Edwin, 1894-- 1938 (Box 27)
  - Balch, Earle H. 1931 (Box 27)
  - Baruch, Bernard Mannes, 1870-1965 1947-1965 (Box 27)
  - Benet, William Rose, 1886-1950 1930 (Box 27)
  - Bliven, Bruce, 1889- 1936 (Box 27)
  - [Bovard], O.K. 1938 (Box 27)
  - Bowers, Claude Gernade, 1878-1958 1933 (Box 27)
  - Brickell, Herschel 1935 (Box 27)
  - Bridges, Robert Seymour, 1844-1930 (Box 27)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963 1940 (Box 27)
  - Broun, Matthew Heywood Campbell, 1888-1939 1936 (Box 27)
  - Bruce, Philip Alexander, 1856-1933 1931 (Box 27)
  - Buckley, William Frank, Jr., 1925-- 1963 (Box 27)
  - Byrd, Harry Flood 1887-1966 (Box 27)
  - Byrd, Richard Evelyn, 1888-1957 1932 (Box 27)
  - Byrnes, James Francis, 1879-- 1947 (Box 27)
  - Cabell, James Branch, 1879-1958 1929-1942 (Box 27)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961 1933 (Box 27)
  - Catton, Bruce, 1899- 1957-1971 (Box 27)
  - Clapper, Raymond 1943 (Box 27)
  - Clay, Lucius DuBignon, 1919-- 1962 (Box 27)
  - Coghlan, Ralph 1941 (Box 27)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1912-- 1962-1971 (Box 27)
  - Croziar, W.P. 1936-1938 (Box 27)
  - Daniels, Jonathan Worth, 1902- 1932-1938 (Box 27)
  - Davis, Burke, 1913- 1962 (Box 27)
  - Dillard, James Hardy, 1856-1940 1934 (Box 27)
  - Dilliard, Irving, 1904- 1936 (Box 27)
  - Dodd, William E. 1933 (Box 27)
  - Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970 1960-1968 (Box 27)
  - Dowd, J.E. 1936 (Box 27)
  - Eaton, G.D. 1928 (Box 27)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1879-1855 1947 (Box 27)
  - Eisenhower, Mamie Geneva (Doud), 1896- 1958-1971 (Box 27)
  - Ethridge, Mark 1933 (Box 27)
  - Fadiman, Clifton, 1904-- 1941 (Box 27)
  - Fischer, John, 1910- 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Fisher, Dorothy (Canfield), 1879-1958 1940 (Box 27)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965 1938 (Box 27)
  - Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1886-1953 1929-1948 (Box 27)
  - [Gilliam], Frank 1961 (Box 27)
  - Gingrich, Arnold, 1903-- 1938 (Box 27)
  - Glasgow, Ellen Anderson Gholson, 1874-1945 1932-1935 (Box 27)
  - Glass, Carter, 1858-1946 1936 (Box 27)
  - Golden, Harry, 1902- 1965 (Box 27)
  - Graham, William Franklin, 1918- 1956-1957 (Box 27)
  - Graham, Frank 1934-1936 (Box 27)
  - Gruening, Ernest, 1887- 1933 (Box 27)
  - Gruenther, Alfred M., 1899- 1958 (Box 27)
  - Gunther, John, 1901- 1958 (Box 27)
  - Hand, Learned 1958 (Box 27)
  - Harris, Julian Earle, 1896- 1933 (Box 27)
  - Harrison, Albertis Sydney, 1907- 1966 (Box 27)
  - Hilton, James, 1900-1954 1950 (Box 27)
  - Hoover, Herbert Clark, 1874-1964 1946-1949 (Box 27)
  - Hoover, John Edgar, 1895- 1958-1964 (Box 27)
  - Howland, William S. 1954 (Box 27)
  - Hoxton, A.R. 1946-1951 (Box 27)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955 1940 (Box 27)
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio, 1911- 1965 (Box 27)
  - Jaffe, Louis, 1933-1934 (Box 27)
  - James, Edwin, L. 1936 (Box 27)
  - Johnson, Gerald White, 1890- 1931-1944 (Box 27)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines, 1908- 1959 (Box 27)
  - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1892- 1938 (Box 27)
  - Kane, Harnett Thomas, 1910- 1961 (Box 27)
  - Kirby, Rollin, 1875-1952 1950 (Box 27)
  - Kirchwey, Freda, 1911- 1928 (Box 27)
  - Krock, Arthur, 1886- 1929-1966 (Box 27)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1893- 1934 (Box 27)
  - Lacy, Ben 1955-1966 (Box 28)
  - Lee, Lawrence, 1903- 1939 (Box 28)
  - Lewis, N. Battle 1934 (Box 28)
  - Lippman, Walter, 1889- 1938-1951 (Box 28)
  - Lowell, A. Lawrence 1910 (Box 28)
  - Lyons, Eugene, 1898- (Box 28)
  - Mallon, Paul 1938 (Box 28)
  - Markel, Lester, 1894- 1938 (Box 28)
  - Marshall, George Catlett, 1880-1959 1947-1955 (Box 28)
  - Maury, Reuben, 1899- 1949 (Box 28)
  - Meloney, Marie M. 1929 (Box 28)
  - Mencken, Henry Louis, 1880-1956 1925-1948 (Box 28)
  - Metcalf, John Calvin, 1863-1949 1932 (Box 28)
  - Milton, George F. 1936 (Box 28)
  - Mitchell, Samuel Chiles 1934 (Box 28)
  - Moore, Robert Walton 1936 (Box 28)
  - Morehouse, Ward, 1899-1966 1938 (Box 28)
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1887- 1958-1970 (Box 28)
  - Murrow, Edward R. 1959 (Box 28)
  - Nevins, Allan, 1890-1971 1933 (Box 28)
  - Nixon, Richard Milhouse, 1913- 1955-1966 (Box 28)
  - Ochs, Adolph Simon, 1858-1935 1932 (Box 28)
  - Odum, Howard Washington 1933 (Box 28)
  - Palmer, Paul 1936 (Box 28)
  - Parker, Robert A. 1930 (Box 28)
  - Pegler, Westbrook, 1891- 1942-1957 (Box 28)
  - Perkins, Frances, 1882-1965 1936 (Box 28)
  - Pollard, John Garland, 1871-1937 1932 (Box 28)
  - Powell, John, 1882-1963 1960-1962 (Box 28)
  - Puller, Lewis B. 1960-1962 (Box 28)
  - Rockefeller, John Davison, 1874-1960 1948 (Box 28)
  - Rogers, William Pierce, 1913- 1958 (Box 28)
  - Romney, George, 1907- 1967 (Box 28)
  - Rusk, Dean, 1909- 1965 (Box 28)
  - Shaw, Albert, 1857-1947 1936 (Box 28)
  - Sheean, Vincent, 1899- 1939 (Box 28)
  - Siegfried, Andre, 1875-1959 1927 (Box 28)
  - Smith, Merriman, 1913- 1963 (Box 28)
  - Stettinius, Edward R., Jr., 1900-1949 1938 (Box 28)
  - Stokes, Thomas, 1906- 1938 (Box 28)
  - Stowe, Leland, 1899- 1936 (Box 28)
  - Strauss, Lewis Lichtenstein, 1896- 1958-1959 (Box 28)
  - Strode, Hudson 1938-1964 (Box 28)
  - Taft, Robert Alphonso, 1889-1953 1952 (Box 28)
  - Thomas, Norman Mattoon, 1884-1968 1937 (Box 28)
  - Thompson, Dorothy, 1894-1961 1936 (Box 28)
  - Thurber, James Grover, 1894-1961 1959 (Box 28)
  - Toynbee, Arnold Joseph, 1889- 1965 (Box 28)
  - Tuchman, Barabara Wertheim, 1912 (Box 28)
  - Willard, Oswald Garrison 1936 (Box 28)
  - Wallace, Dewitt, 1889- 1955 (Box 28)
  - Wallace, Tom 1936 (Box 28)
  - Waymack, W.W. 1938 (Box 28)
  - Wertenbaker, Thomas Jefferson, 1879-1966 1932 (Box 28)
  - Wheeler-Bennett, Sir John, 1902-- 1938 (Box 28)
  - White, William Allen,1868-1944 1936-1939 (Box 28)
  - Whitney, John Hay 1960 (Box 28)
  - Willkie, Wendell Lewis, 1892-1944 1911 (Box 28)
  - Woodward, Comer Vann, 1908- 1971 (Box 28)
  - Young, Owen D., 1874-1962 1937 (Box 28)